Esther (Yunjung) Kim

Houston, TX 77041 | 832-682-5811 | <u>estherkimyunjung@gmail.com</u> <u>Portfolio</u> | <u>Github</u> | <u>Medium</u> | <u>Linkedin</u> | Green Card Holder

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Full Stack Web Developer with a passion for learning. With experience in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming and a background in finance and business. I bring strong skills in project management, team planning, strategy, analysis, and organization to achieve specific goals and objectives on time. Collaborative and diligent team player who is creative and problem solves well under pressure to deliver high-quality work.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript, ES6, React.js, Redux, React Native, Node.js, SQL, Postgresql, Express, HTML, CSS, Semantic UI/Material UI React, jQuery, Ruby on Rails, Socket.io/WSS, Java, JSP, Bootstrap, Github, Git, Firebase, Agile/SCRUM Workflow

KEY PROJECTS

Home1800 - Github / Demo

Clients can search for and review property listings, make appointments, and communicate with real estate agents.

- Created Ruby on Rails API backend with endpoints for users (client and agent), companies, properties, and appointments. Node.js backend with node mailer for email and socket.io for the chat server.
- Built React frontend with JWT authentication to manage user logins. Google Maps API to show the location and provide additional information to the property listings.
- Utilized Material UI, Semantic UI, and Bootstrap React for the UI framework.

Amazon-clone - Github / Website

A fully functioning e-commerce website where users can shop, make payments, and update their shopping cart.

- Developed Node.js API backend with express server framework and Axios (send asynchronous HTTP requests to REST endpoints and perform CRUD operations), authentication, database, function, and hosting with Firebase.
- Utilized React.js (Redux, Hooks, React-router) for the Frontend. Payment processing with Stripe API.
- Worte custom CSS using flexbox to display Responsive website.

Uber-clone - Github

Traveler allows comparing the ride options and makes decisions in their budget. (A mobile app currently in development)

- Leveraged React Native(Expo) to build the mobile application and Tailwind CSS to design the UI.
- Used Redux to respond to and modify state changes.
- Created embedded Google Map and utilized Google API for direction, places, distance matrix, and autocomplete.

EXPERIENCE

Genesis Home Loan, Mortgage Loan Processor - Houston, TX

November 2015 - September 2017

- Prepared documents for underwriting by verifying client income, credit reports, and other information.
- Completed loan submission packages to meet strict deadlines 100% of the time.
- Supported customers personally with prompt responses and resolutions to issues, resulting in 100% closeouts of loans

Quiznos, Franchise Owner - Houston, TX

April 2006 - July 2015

- Analyzed market to improved marketing, excellent customer service strategies, and maintaining top food quality to increased sales revenue resulting in a 25% increase in sales.
- Recruited and developed successful operations staff to handle day-to-day business operations.
- Recognized and maintained Top 5 franchise status in regional store sales throughout the ownership of the business.

Dong K. Kim, CPA, CPA Associate - Houston, TX

January 2003 - April 2006

- Assisted CPA with tax returns and financial statements for individuals, partnerships, and corporations.
- Set up a new tax program to help expedite filing W-2 forms, quarterly payroll, and sales tax returns to the IRS.
- Established friendly customer relationships for maintaining and organizing detailed bookkeeping of accounting records to accurately prepare clients' monthly sales reports and consolidated monthly balance sheets.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School, Full-Stack Web Development Certificate - Houston, TX

April 2020 - July 2020

Encore Software Service, Inc., Frontend Web Development Certificate - South Korea

March 2019 - November 2019

Konyang University, BS, Computer Science / Teacher's Certificate - South Korea

March 1997 - February 2000